<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="idiomList">
        <item name="i1">Call it a day/night;Stop, to stop working, to quit work and go home;\"I\'m tired. Let\'s call it a day.\";تعطيل كردن كار، متوقف كردن فعاليت در حال انجام، ادامه ندادن كاري كه هنوز تمام نشده;\"من خسته ام، ديگه كار تعطيل.\"</item>
        <item name="i2">Out of the blue;When something happens randomly and unexpected;\"A great idea just came to me out of the blue.\";بصورت سرزده، بدون هماهنگي، يهو;\"همين الان يهو يه ايده عالي به ذهنم رسيد.\"</item>
        <item name="i3">Come on;Stop, please, hurry, go faster;\"Come on, I only have a few minutes before I must go.\";\"Come on, stop doing that.\";بس كن ديگه، عجله كن، زود باش ديگه;\"زود باش ديگه، من فقط چند دقيقه قبل رفتن وقت دارم.\"\n\"بس كن ديگه، اين كار رو نكن.\"</item>
        <item name="i4">Beat around the bush;Avoiding the main topic. Not speaking directly about the issue;\"Come on, stop beating around the bush and answer my question.\";طفره رفتن، پيچوندن، به كوچه علی چپ زدن;\"زود باش، طفره نرو و جواب سوالمو بده.\"</item>
        <item name="i5">Make ends meet;To earn and spend equal amounts of money;\"I have to work at two jobs to make ends meet.\";گذران زندگی کردن, به زور سر ماه رو به ته ماه رسوندن;\"برای گذران زندگی مجبورم دوتا کار داشته باشم.\"</item>
        <item name="i6">Clear the air;Discuss something that was causing people to feel upset;\"There seems to have been a misunderstanding. I\'d like to explain what happened, just to clear the air.\";ناراحتي و شك و ترديد را كنار گذاشتن، رفع كدورت ها;\"به نظر ميرسه كه سوءتفاهمي پيش آمده. دوست دارم توضيح بدم كه چي شده، فقط محض رفع كدورت ها.\"</item>
        <item name="i7">Early Bird;A person who is early, or gets up early;\"Dave was in class 30 minutes before anyone else. What an early bird!\";سحرخيز بودن;\"ديويد 30 دقيقه قبل از بقيه تو كلاس بود، چه سحرخيز!\"</item>
        <item name="i8">Flesh and blood;Someone from your family, a relative;\"I must help him. After all, he\'s my own flesh and blood.\";از يك گوشت و خون بودن، داشتن رابطه خانودگي يا فاميلي;\"من بايد بهش كمك كنم، بهرحال ما از يك گوشت و خون هستيم.\"</item>
        <item name="i9">In cold blood;With no compassion or mercy. Usually associated with ruthless murder;\"The assassin was evil. He killed him in cold blood.\";با بي رحمي تمام ،با بي احساسي تمام;\"اون قاتل خيلي خبيث بود، با بي رحمي تمام اون رو کشت.\"</item>
        <item name="i10">Get to the bottom of something;To get an understanding of the causes of something;\"We are not sure what happened, but we intend to get to the bottom of this.\";به درك كامل رسيدن، فهميدن چيزي، به دليل يا مشكل چيزي پي بردن;\"ما نميدونيم چي شده، ولي قصد داريم سر در بياوريم.\"</item>
        <item name="i11">Bread and butter;The essential, sustaining element, Someone`s livelihood;\"The quality of the schools is the bread and butter of town property values.\";عنصر اصلي، درآمد اصلي، نون و آب;\"كيفيت مدارس عنصر اصلي تعيين كننده قيمت ملك شهراست.\"</item>
        <item name="i12">Give me a break;Don\'t expect me to believe or agree with that;\"You\'re going to run in tomorrow\'s marathon? Give me a break!\";جون من دست بردار، جون من بيخيال، عمرا;\"تو ميخواي تو دو ماراتون فردا شركت كني؟ جون من بيخيال!\"</item>
        <item name="i13">Enough is enough;This should stop;\"I have listened to his complaints for years but enough is enough.\";ديگه كافيه، اين بايد تموم بشه;\"سالهاست كه به غرولنداش گوش دادم، ديگه كافيه!\"</item>
        <item name="i14">Hang out;Be together, spend time with each other;\"I\'m gonna hang out with my best friend this weekend.\";گذراندن وقت، با هم بودن;\"آخر هفته ميخوام وقتمو با بهترين دوستم بگذرونم.\"</item>
        <item name="i15">Get something off your chest;Explain something that is bothering you;\"Jack, you don\'t seem happy. Is there something you would like to get off your chest?\";خالي كردن سفره دل، زدن حرفايي كه فرد رو اذيت ميكنن;\"جک، به نظر خوشحال نميايي. چيزي تو دلته كه بخواي بگي؟\"</item>
        <item name="i16">Makes someone\'s day;Make someone happy;\"Your letter made my day!\";خيلي خوشحال كردن، راضي كردن;\"نامه ات خيلي خوشحالم كرد!\"</item>
        <item name="i17">As a matter of fact;Actually, in addition to what has been said;\"As a matter of fact, we have been to the sports stadium many times.\";در حقيقت، علاوه بر اون;در حقيقت، ما بارها به استاديوم ورزشي رفتيم.\"</item>
        <item name="i18">For that matter;Used to indicate that a subject, though mentioned second, is as relevant as the first;\"Mikael is quite arrogant. So is his sister, for that matter.\";همچنين، به همون صورت، بعلاوه;\"مایکل واقعا مغروره. خواهرش هم همينطور.\"</item>
        <item name="i19">Better off;To be in a better situation than before;\"My friend would be better off if he sold his old car and bought a new one.\";بهتر خواهد بود، در شرايط بهتري خواهد بود;\"براي دوستم بهتره كه ماشين قديمي خودشو بفروشه و يك جديد بخره.\"</item>
        <item name="i20">Come up with;To produce or find a thought or idea or answer;\"I tried to come up with a name for the new magazine.\";كشف كردن، تدبير كردن، پيدا كردن;\"تلاش كردم كه اسمی براي مجله جديد پيدا كنم.\"</item>
        <item name="i21">To make sense;To be logical or rational;\"The manager\'s new proposal doesn\'t make sense!\";عاقلانه بودن، معني دار بودن، منطقي بودن;\"پيشنهاد جديد مديرعاقلانه نيست.\"</item>
        <item name="i22">More or less;Somewhat, to some extend, approximately, mostly;\"I more or less have decided to study business next year.\";\"They more or less are the same.\";تا حدودي، تقريبا، براي بيان عدم قطعيت;\"من تقريبا تصميم گرفتم سال ديگه اقتصاد بخونم.\"\n\"اون دوتا تا حدودي شبيه هم هستند.\"</item>
        <item name="i23">Run into (Something or Somebody);To meet or find someone or something by chance, to experience or encounter something;\"The mechanic ran into trouble when he was fixing my car.\";\"I ran into some interesting facts while I was researching my essay.\";برخوردن به كسي، برخود با چيزي;\"مكانيك وقيتي داشت ماشين منو تعمير ميكرد با مشكلي مواجه شد.\"\n\"وقتي داشتم مقالم رو تحقيق ميكردم به يكسري واقعيات جالب برخوردم.\"</item>
        <item name="i24">Shape up or ship out;This expression is used to warn someone that if they do not improve their ways, they will have to leave their job;\"When Daniel started neglecting the customers, he was told to shape up or ship out.\";اگر رفتارت را درست نكني اخراجي;\"وقتي دانيال شروع به بي اعتنايي به مشتري ها كرد، بهش گفته شد كه يا رفتارش رو درست كنه يا اخراج ميشه.\"</item>
        <item name="i25">Easier said than done;Be more easily talked about than put into practice;\"Yes, we must find a cure for cancer, but it\'s easier said than done.\";گفتنش آسونه;\"آره، ما بايد براي سرطان درماني پيدا كنيم، ولي گفتنش آسونه.\"</item>
        <item name="i26">Steal someone\'s thunder;To take credit for something someone else did;\"It was Jacob’s idea but they stole his thunder and turned it into a massive advertising campaign without giving him any credit.\";نتيجه و يا دسترنج كس ديگيري را به نام خود ثبت كردن، توجه را از شخصي  ربودن;\"اين ايده یعقوب بود ولي اونا نظرشو بدون اينكه هيچ افتخاري براش داشته باشه تبديل به يك كمپين بزرگ تبليغالتي كردند.\"</item>
        <item name="i27">When pigs fly;This idiom basically means that something will never happen;\"Sure, Tracy will pay for the lunch, when pigs fly.\";عمرا، هرگز، دلالت بر اتفاقي غير ممكن دارد، وقتي پشت گوشت رو ديدي;\"حتما، تریسی پول ناهار رو ميده، وقتي پشت گوشت رو ديدي.\"</item>
        <item name="i28">Costs an arm and a leg;Aggressively expensive, unexpectedly expensive;\"Antique gifts here cost an arm and a leg.\";قيمت خون بودن چيزي، خيلي خيلي گرون بودن چيزي;\"هديه هاي آنتيك اينجا قيمت خون ادميزاده.\"</item>
        <item name="i29">(To) get the ball rolling;To get started;\"Let\'s get the ball rolling by putting up some posters.\";\"If we don\'t get the ball rolling on our vacation plans soon, we\'ll end up going nowhere.\";شروع كردن چيزي;\"بياييد با نصب چند تا پوستر كار رو شروع كنيم.\"\n\"اگر زود برنامه ريزي تعطيلاتمون رو شروع نكنيم، آخرش هيچ جا نميريم.\"</item>
        <item name="i30">(To) have a heart of gold;To be very kind and giving;\"Pear has a heart of gold and always thinks of others before himself.\";\"You adopted five children from a Romanian orphanage? You\'ve got a heart of gold!\";دست و دلباز بودن، مهربان بودن بودن، بزرگ منش بودن;\"پییر خيلي مهربونه و هميشه قبل از خودن به ديگران فكر ميكنه.\"\n\"تو از يك يتيم خونه رمانيايي پنچ تا بچه رو به سرپرستي قبول كردي؟ تو واقعا دست و دلبازي!\"</item>
        <item name="i31">(To) lose one\'s touch;To no longer be able to do something well;\"In his latest book, Mark seems to have lost his touch for creating interesting characters.\";از دست دادن يك مهارت، ضعيف شدن تو انجام كاري كه قبلا خوب قادر به انجامش بوده ايد;\"مارک تو كتاب آخرش به نظر مياد مهارتش رو تو خلق شخصيت هاي جذاب از دست داده.\"</item>
        <item name="i32">Get it out of your system;To do something you’ve wanted to do for a long time and don’t want to postpone any longer;\"I wasn’t sure how she was going to react, but I had to get it out of my system, so I told her I had betrayed her.\";خلاص شدن از احساسات منفي، خالي كردن خود;\"نميدونستم چطور عكس العمل نشون ميده، ولي مجبود بودم خودمو خالي كنم، پس بهش گفتم كه بهش خيانت كردم.\"</item>
        <item name="i33">Pull yourself together;To calm down and behave normally;\"I understand you’ve had a bad day, but pull yourself together and get on with your job, will you?\";خودتو جمع و جور كن، به خودت مسلط شو، خودتو كنترل كن;\"ميدونم روز بدي داشته اي، ولي به خودت مسلط شو و برس به كارت، باشه؟\"</item>
        <item name="i34">Go down in flames;To end or fail suddenly and spectacularly;\"Sam wanted to become Managing Director, but his career went down in flames when they found out he’d been leaking information to our competitors.\";نابود شدن، بطور كلي از بين رفتن، تركيدن;\"سام ميخواست مدير عامل بشه، ولي وقتي فهميدن به رقيبامون اطلاعات ميداده شغلش كلا نابود شد.\"</item>
        <item name="i35">Easy come, easy go;Something that has been attained easily will too, disappear easily;\"Samuel lost in one night all of the money he had won in the lottery, easy come easy go!\";باد آورده را با باد میبرد;\"سامول تمام پولهايي رو كه تو لاتري برنده شده بود يه شبه باخت، باد آورده رو باد میبره.\"</item>
        <item name="i36">Speak of the devil;When the person you’re just talking about actually turns up at that moment;\"Sam: I haven`t seen David for years.\"\n\"Peter: Oh look, there he is! Speak of the devil.\";حلال زاده هست;\"سام: داوود رو سالهاست ندیدم.\"\n\"پیتر: نگاه کن, اوناهاش! حلال زادهست.\"</item>
        <item name="i37">Once in a blue moon;An event that happens infrequently;\"I only go to the cinema once in a blue moon.\";دلالت بر اتفاق خیلی نادر دارد;\"من خیلی خیلی نادر به سینما میروم.\"</item>
        <item name="i38">To feel under the weather;To not feel well;\"Your teacher couldn`t make it today, she felt a bit under the weather.\";ناخوش بودن, احوال مناسبی نداشتن;\"معلمتون امروز نتونست بیاد, یکم ناخوش بود.\"</item>
        <item name="i39">Miss the boat;To make a mistake, to be wrong;\"If George thinks he can discipline them, he has missed the boat!\";سخت در اشتباه بودن;\"اگه جرج فكر كرده ميتونه اونا رو منظم كنه، سخت در اشتباهه!\"</item>
        <item name="i40">Scratch someone’s back;Do someone a favor in hopes that a favor will be returned;\"You do the dishes and I`ll do your homework, OK? You scratch my back and I`ll scratch yours.\";دم كسي را ديدن به انتظار جبران طرف مقابل;\"تو ظرفهارو بشور و منم تكليف خونتو انجام ميدم، باشه؟ تو يه حالي بهم بده، منم هواتو دارم.\"</item>
        <item name="i41">Pull someone\'s leg;Play a joke on somebody, tease someone;\"Do you really want to quit or you\'re just pulling my leg?\";دست انداختن كسي، سر كار گذاشتن كسي;\"آيا واقعا ميخواي استعفا بعدي یا سر كارمون گذاشتي؟\"</item>
        <item name="i42">Break a leg;Used to wish someone, such as an actor, success in a performance;\"You are up next to perform on stage Merry? Break a leg.\";آرزوي موفقيت براي فردي كه قرار است روي صحنه اجرايي داشته باشد;\"نفر بعدي تويي كه بري بالا اجرا كني مریم؟ موفق باشي.\"</item>
        <item name="i43">A piece of cake;Something that is very easy;\"The English test was a piece of cake.\";مثل آب خوردن بودن، خيلي آسون بودن;\"امتحان انگليسي من مثل آب خوردن بود.\"</item>
        <item name="i44">Let the cat out of the bag;To accidentally reveal a secret;\"I let the cat out of the bag about their wedding plans.\";اتفاقي لو دادن يك راز، دهن لقی کردن;\"من اتفاقي برنامه هاي مراسم ازدواجشون رو لو دادم.\"</item>
        <item name="i45">To hit the nail on the head;To describe exactly what is causing a situation or problem;\"Micky doesn\'t say much, but every now and then he hits the nail right on the head.\";زدن وسط خال, اشاره به اصل مطلب;\"مکی زیاد حرف نمیزنه, ولی هر از گاهی میزنه وسط خال.\"</item>
        <item name="i46">The last Straw;The final problem in a series of problems;\"It\'s the last straw that breaks the camel\'s back.\";خان هفتم, آخرین مرحله;\"خان هفتمه که کمر شکنه.\"</item>
        <item name="i47">Hit the books;To study hard;\"I gotta go home and hit the books.\";حسابی درس خوندن;\"باید برم خونه و حسابی درس بخونم.\"</item>
        <item name="i48">Best of both worlds;A situation wherein one can enjoy two different opportunities;\"I got the best of both worlds during my trip to the USA, as I got to relax on the beach in California, and party in Las Vegas!\";هم خدا و هم خرما رو داشتن, از هر دو طرف سود بردن;\"تو سفرم به آمریکا هم خدا رو داشتم هم خرما, چون هم تونستم تو سواحل کالیفرنیا ریلکس کنم و هم تو لاس وگاس خوش بگذرونم!\"</item>
        <item name="i49">Ditch someone;To break plans with someone without telling them;\"I was supposed to meet my friends to see Spiderman 3 last night, but they ditched me! I’m so mad!\";پیچوندن کسی;\"دیشب قرار بود با دوستام بریم فیلم مرد عنکبوتی 3 رو ببینیم, ولی منو پیچوندن! اعصاب ندارم!\"</item>
        <item name="i50">Nailed it;To do something perfectly or successfully;\"I wish you nail your performance today, Aida!\";ترکوندن, پکوندن;\"آرزو میکنم اجرای امروزت رو بترکونی آیدا!\"</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
